

Bc. Jakub Pradeniak

15. 8. 1991

Jamartice 94, 795 01 Rýmařov jakub.pradeniak@bluenet.cz, pradeniak@seznam.cz +420 728 069 811

Job experience

2010 - still BlueNet.cz (formerly PhoenixDesign.cz)

Software developer, Project manager - my job is to design and develop applications and ISes, UI prototyping and also project management (family business - associate)

(from 2010 to 2016 we have worked under Naše Dobroty brand, then we switched to PhoenixDesign and lastly to BlueNet.cz)

2017 - still Office of Labour of Czech Republic, regional branch Ostrava

During my programming break (not programming full time) I made decision that I want to help people. In the beginning as Career specialist then as Specialist of social benefits at Office of Labour of Czech Republic

2016 - 2017 Česká Spořitelna

In this time period I have temporarily left my full time career as IT specialist and started to work as bank advisor - specialist of financial products (I had certification of Czech national bank - expired)

2013 - 2014 Seznam.cz, a. s.

Analyst of machine processed data (details can not be provided - signed agreement of confidentiality; alongside with studies)

2012 - 2014 Self employed (freelancing)

Software development, web apps development, IT consultant (alongside with studies)

Education Moravská vysoká škola Olomouc

At MVŠO I studied Business economics and management. At 2021 I graduated with honors and achieved Bachelors title.

Palacky university in Olomouc

At UPOL I studied Applied Informatics. The study was very beneficial from the point of view of algorithms and mathematics. I learned to program in C, C ++, C # and several other languages. I ended my studies, because at the time of my studies I started to focus on web applications, which were only marginally mentioned at UPOL at that time.

Grammary school at Bruntál

I graduated from IT, math and english

IT skills PHP HTML5 CSS3

	Sass	JS ES6	Relational databases
	Figma prototyping	MySQL	UI a UX designing
General skills	React	C/C++	UnrealEngine
	Kotlin	Network managament	
	Presentation and communication skills	MS Office	OS Windows, Linux
	Data processing/analysis	lmage and video processing	

In general I work with information technology at higher than user level and I can very quickly learn to work with any software.

Languages English

Fluent in words and writing (I plan to get a C1 certificate, ideally a C2)

Czech

Native speaker

Licenses and certificates

Licenses and Drivers license - group B (Czech drivers license)

Google Apps certificate

I obtained this certificate during my time in the Česká Spořitelna.

Google Analytics Academy

Google Tag Manager certificate.

About me

I have been developing web applications and information systems for over ten years. Most of the time I worked as a full stack developer with orientation on PHP and SQL on the server side. On the frontend I worked for a long time without any frameworks, only in HTML, CSS (or Sass) and JavaScript.

In PHP, I programmed my own MVC for our family business and also a JS library similar to jQuery, which, however, always processes data as an array and is significantly smaller (easy to use built-in methods for arrays).

I am now working on the transition to Frontend. I was fascinated by the React framework, so I decided to specialize in it. In addition to React, I am interested in NoSQL application solutions (MongoDB).

After ending my studies at UPOL, I felt the need to change the environment, so for some time I only worked only part-time in IT. I did programming after my job and in my free time, I worked mainly on projects that I enjoyed and for our small family business.

Now I want to return to the full-time IT profession - web application programming. Ideally a front end, but I also like to learn new technologies and programming languages (now I'm interested in Kotlin and Android development).